KUMARESH BABU N S (1) Featured

Professional Cloud Application Engineer with more than 5+ years of experience in the field of Cloud Computing and Software Development. Experienced on working in developing the highly scalable cloud applications.



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Notice Period: 3 Months **Current Company: Mphasis**

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Technical Architecture, Cloud Computing, Algorithm Development, AWS, Docker, Cloud Native, pivotal cloud foundry

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Professional Cloud Application Engineer with more than 5+ years of experience in the field of Cloud Computing and Software Development. Experienced on working in developing the highly scalable cloud applications using the industry standard best practices. Achieved AWS Certified Machine Learning Specialty Certification and AWS Certified Developer Associate.

Work Experience

Mphasis as Software Engineer Jun 2019 to Till Date

- Hands-on Experience on working in developing and deploying Cloud Native applications using 12 Factor Application
- Incorporated the various AWS Cloud Services such as S3, EC2 and RDS in the project using Spring Cloud AWS. Configured to use AWS IAM Role in the application to authenticate AWS Services.
- Have used Spring Security framework to configure and secure the application's REST API using JSON Web Token.
- Worked on Docker to create the Dockerfile for the application as part of deployment part.
- Refactored the Spring legacy web application to Cloud enabled Spring Boot applications.

NTT DATA as Software Dev. Analyst Nov 2015 to Jun 2019

I've worked as Cloud App Developer for 3 years and 3 months in the field of Amazon Web Services and Pivotal Cloud Foundry. Experienced on developing and deploying Cloud Native apps using Spring Boot and 12 factor App Principles. Experienced on developing Microservices using Spring Cloud Services in Pivotal Cloud Foundry.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Jerusalem College of Engineering, Chennai in 2015

PG: PG Diploma (Computers), Correspondence/Distance Learning from International Institute of Information Technology (IIIT), Bangalore in 2020

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

AWS Certified Developer Associate

WEB COMPONENT DEVELOPMENT USING JAVA TECHNOLOGIES

AWS Certified Machine Learning Specialty

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	sion Last Used Experience	
AMAZON Web Services		2021	5 Year(s) 1 Month(s)
DOCKER		2021	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Jenkins		2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Spring Cloud		2021	5 Year(s) 1 Month(s)
spring boot		2021	5 Year(s) 1 Month(s)
Pivotal Cloud Foundry		2019	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Sourashtra	Proficient			
English	Proficient			
Tamil	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: Containerized Management Automation Suite

Client: Mercer

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2019 - Till Date Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 2

Role: Programmer Skill Used: Amazon S3, Amazon ElastiCache and Amazon EC2

Developed the stateful components for the project using ReactJS. Role Description: *

- Created the REST APIs to use Azure REST APIs to automatically create the build pipeline and release pipeline for the customer's projects.
- Have used Spring Data Orient DB Graph QL

Project Details: A Tool to automatically generate Dockerfile and Docker Compose for Apps.

Project Title: Refactoring and Migrating Apps to Fidelity Private Cloud

Client: Fidelity Investments

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Apr 2017 - Jun 2019 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 2

Skill Used: Spring Cloud, Spring Boot, Docker, AWS

Role Description: * Refactored the spring boot app based on 12 factor app principles.

- Removed the duplicate code from an existing spring legacy web applications.
- Delivered the quality code by refactoring the spring legacy web applications.

Defined Benefits project was segregated into a small spring legacy web projects for migrating into Project Details: Customers Private Cloud.

Implemented Fidelitys provided Spring Boot framework to all spring legacy web projects.

Removed the hardcoded connection information from an application and replaced with the Key/Value pair. Key/Value are configured in Customers Config Manager to fetch connection details from App runtime.

Decoupled the applications functionality into separate spring boot app to remove unrelated function dependency.

Project Title: Cloud Native Apps on Pivotal Cloud Foundry

Client: Avis Budget Group Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2016 - Mar 2017 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Pivotal Cloud Foundry, Spring Boot and Spring Cloud

Role Description: * Developed Cloud Native Apps by using Spring Boot, Spring Cloud and 12 Factor App Principles.

Developed Multiple Spring Boot Applications for each service to show case to our Customer.

Project Details: Purpose of this project is to showcase to our customer about the benefits of leveraging 12 Factor App Principles and advantages of using Pivotal Cloud Foundry.

Service Instances were created for RabbitMQ, Send Grid, MySQL, New Relic, Spring Cloud Services and Redis are available in PCF Apps Manager marketplace.

Added spring-cloud-spring-service-connector dependency to the apps classpath for binding the application with the services in Pivotal Cloud Foundry Environment.

In order to make zero change in applications and to deploy PCF, I have created multiple profiles in all Spring Boot applications to work both in Developers environment and in cloud.

Developed Spring Cloud Microservices by using Spring Cloud Services from PCF Apps Manager marketplace. Spring Cloud Config are used for storing the apps configuration details.

Project Title: Image Processing Application using Amazon SQS, Amazon EC2 and Amazon S3

Client: Dell Services

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2016 - May 2016 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 2

Skill Used: AWS, Spring Boot, Core Java

Role Description: * Followed 12 Factor App Principles to implement the best practices on developing the application.

Launched an Amazon Linux EC2 instance in public

Project Details: Image Processing Application is used to resize the images using AWS Cloud Services.

Amazon EC2 instance was used to launch an application in AWS Cloud. AWS IAM role was attached to Amazon EC2 instance with access permissions for Amazon S3 bucket and Amazon SQS queues.

Oracle Java 1.8 and Apache Tomcat server 1.8 was installed on Amazon EC2 instance to run Image Processing Application.

User is allowed to upload the images to Amazon S3 bucket and the object key is stored in Amazon SQS queue as inbox. By using original image, User can able to resize the image and upload it back to same bucket by replacing with an original image. Object key of resized image are stored in Amazon SQS queue as outbox.

Object are set as public access to the users by modifying the bucket policy.

The user can able to download the resized image from Amazon S3 bucket.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Countries: India

Physically Challenged: No

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time